Head of Systems Development

ALEXANDROS SOUMPLIS

EXPERIENCE

National Infrastructures for Research and Technology (GRNET)

Head of Systems Development | since August 2018

Team lead of cloud engineering team that designed, built and operates the first OpenStack public cloud for the academic and research community in Greece. Currently runs with 220+ compute hosts, offering almost 10K CPU cores, 44TB RAM and 1,5PB storage. The project also required the full deployment of the operations ecosystem, including health and perfromance monitoring, log aggregation and analysis, security audit and other.

Stavros Niarchos Foundation Cultural Center (SNFCC) Chief Technology Officer | January 2016 - August 2018

Executive role in charge of the technology delpoyment and operation in the SNFCC premises, hosting National Library of Greece and the Greek National Opera. We provided full infrastructure and IT services to both organizations and also visitor, exceeding 2M per year.

National Documentation Centre (EKT)

Head of NOC / Senior Systems Engineer | April 2007 - December 2015

Initially senior systems engineer and then Head of Network Operations Center and in charge of design, deploy and operations of the core ICT infrastructure, ICT services and digital data services. Main responsibilities including devops, virtualization, cloud storage, web services, high availability and scalability, monitoring and capacity planning

Ideal Systems S.A.

Systems Engineer (Unix) | May 2002 - February 2015

FORTHnet S.A.

Technical Support | July 1999 - April 2002

EDUCATION

Hellenic Open University

MSC "Pervasive and Mobile Computing Systems" | since 2019

National and Kapodistrian University of Athens

About me

I like to consider myself an IT enthusiast and certainly a Linux expert. I have gone through the whole path of engineering, starting as a helpdesk operator for dial up Internet connections and now I am a cloud engineer with particular focus on OpenStack and Kubernetes. I like spending my spare time with family and do various nature-related activities, such as scuba diving, canyoning, sailing etc.